Chan Young (Brian) Ji

<u>jicy@uci.edu</u>

408.807.5937

in Chan Young Ji

21 California Avenue, Irvine, CA 92612

PROFILE

Senior undergraduate in Computer Science & Engineering with a passion for turning creative ideas into practical applications. Proficient in programming and software development in multiple languages such as Python, Java, C++, and more. Additionally, experience in handling hardware through electrical engineering courses and robotics club. Strong leadership skills gained from leading a college club committee and military background.

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine

Irvine, CA | Sep 2019 - Jun 2024

B.S. in Computer Science & Engineering GPA: 3.76/4.0

The King's Academy

Sunnyvale, CA | Aug 2016 - Jun 2019

American Community School (ACS) International School Doha

Doha, Qatar | Aug 2013 - Jun 2016

EXPERIENCE

Informatics & Computer Science Learning Assistant

University of California, Irvine Irvine, CA | Sep 2023 - Mar 2024

- Peer educator, providing guidance and mentorship to fellow students while fostering a collaborative learning environment
- Assisting professor and Teaching Assistants every week to ensure seamless execution of academic activities
- · Receiving Pedagogy/Training Course

UCI KSEA Youth Group Leader

Korean-American Scientist & Engineers Association (KSEA) Irvine, CA | Mar 2023 - present

- · Organizing and managing STEM-related events as a member of the leader's committee
- Leading team members to plan, generate, and collaborate innovative ideas for new STEM events and projects

Lance Corporal (KOR) / Sergeant (US)

Republic of Korea Army (ROKA) Pocheon, South Korea | Jul 2021 - Jan 2023

- Positioned as Squad Leader and Rifleman, mainly tasked with supporting the platoon leader, training and leading squad soldiers
- Proficiently managed communication and radio devices during training operations
- Created technical documentation using Excel and Word to maintain accurate and organized records

Engineer Student

BlueStamp Engineering San Jose, CA | Jun 2018 - Jul 2018

- Actively engaged in interactive sessions with robotics and engineering industry professionals, gaining hands-on experience and collaboration
- Engineered a miniature RC car utilizing Arduino, as a personal project based on the experience

Student

Science Olympiad Club Sunnyvale, CA | 2016 - 2019

 Engaged in group discussions, practices, competitions, and tournaments toward solving science problems

SKILLS

Technical

- Python
- Java
- JavaScript
- · React & ReactNative
- C/C++
- Prolog
- LISP
- Arduino
- x86 Assembly Language
- Verilog/System Verilog
- WordPress
- · Adobe Photoshop
- · Microsoft Office Suite

Personal

- Adept at computer programming
- Excellent communication skills
- · Quick learner
- Collaborative team player with strong leadership qualities
- Responsible and knows how to prioritize
- Strong problem-solving and decision-making skills
- Creative and innovative thinker
- Hard-working and self-discipline

Interests

- Actively acquiring proficiency in new coding languages (currently studying React)
- Video game development
- Reading and writing novels
- Movie critique
- Traveling

HONORS

- Principal's List 2016–2019
- National Honor Society 2017 – 2019
- MMA American Math Competition 2017-2019

LANGUAGES

 Fluent in English & Korean

Gallery Exhibition Interpreter

The Tech Museum of Innovation San Jose, CA | 2017 - 2018

- Provided knowledgeable guidance to guests, helping them navigate through the galleries and offering information on exhibitions
- Gained experience with managing and speaking to groups of visitors, maintaining a friendly and polite manner

VOLUNTEER & COMMUNITY SERVICE

House Building

Tecate, Mexico | 2016 - 2019

- Participated in a home-building campaign for the homeless in Tecate
- Served as an electric technician, installing power sockets and bulbs throughout the built house

Auction Staff Assistant

Qatar Charity Doha, Qatar | 2015

- · Assisted with auction coordination from seating arrangements to inviting bidders
- · Communicate and managed client information